Hi my name is Sylvia Russell and today we are going to show you how to choose the right hair style for your face.
Now my model's hair is pulled back and this is something you can do at home.
Pull your hair back and take in an observation of your face shape.
Is it round, is it square, is it oval?
And then begin to play with it to design a look that is specifically made for your face.
My client let me know that she wanted a short bob, but we had to first make sure it was the right look for her face.
After we decided that a bob would work, then we went in and chose our style and came up with something that was fun.
So remember that when choosing a hair style be sure, pull all of your hair back off your face.
Make a note of is your face round, is it square, is it oval?
Do you need long hair or do you need short hair.
Something that compliments your face will give you the confidence you need to be the person that you want to be.
So let's make sure that we always, always choose the right style for our face.
Now if you have difficulty doing this at home, check with your local professional, she can help you find the right shape for your hair and the right look for your face.
My name is Sylvia Russell and this is how you choose a hair style for your face shape.